□ timothy.giles.12@cnu.edu
□ tgiles.github.io/

First generation graduate from Christopher Newport University with Bachelor's and Master's degrees in Computer Science. Self-starter with entrepreneurial spirit. Seven years of work experience in varied fields such as tutoring, teaching, and software engineering. Diversified skill-sets covering object-oriented programming, functional programming, agile methodology, data structures with an emphasis on graphs, and problem solving.

Education

Academic Qualifications...

Christopher Newport University

M.S. in Computer Science, GPA: 3.90

Thesis: Planning Footsteps of Humanoid Robots

Christopher Newport University

B.S. in Computer Science, Cum Laude, GPA: 3.52

Newport News, VA

Aug. 2016 - May 2018

Newport News, VA

Aug. 2012 - May 2016

Notable Projects.....

Masters Thesis: 'Planning Footsteps of Humanoid Robots'

I worked with Team ViGIR's open source footstep planner to create an accurate configuration for a small laboratory robot, as well as fix bugs that prevented accurate 2D planning. This involved learning about many different frameworks and systems to understand the project. Additionally, I implemented a custom plugin in the system.

o Undergraduate Capstone: 'Data Visualization of Theoretical High-Energy Physics Papers' Using tools such as JavaScript, PHP, MySQL, Bootstrap3, and D3js, I was able to generate a graph of archived papers in a large database, linked by citations. The intent was to create a visual gatekeeping system for academics.

Previous Employment

Port Technology Services

Norfolk, VA

Software Engineer

May 2017-Nov. 2017

Developed front-ends for web applications using Angular 2/4+, Redux, and TypeScript. Debugged our CI/CD pipeline which consist of TeamCity and Octopus Deploy. Helped establish JIRA as the primary issue tracker and helped develop the workflow for issues. Worked with .NET Framework/ASP.NET/.NET Core and helped debug back-end software.

Christopher Newport University

Newport News, VA

Graduate Lab Assistant

Aug. 2016-Aug. 2017

Instructed students in intermediate Java concepts: Inheritance, polymorphism, fundamental abstract data containers, file I/O, etc. Additionally, taught students how to use basic version control: adding, pulling, pushing, and merging simple conflicts.

Christopher Newport University

Newport News, VA

Computer Science Tutor

Sep. 2014-Aug. 2016

Primarily tutored students on Java but included JavaScript and Python as needed.

iD Tech Camps

Williamsburg, VA

Lead Instructor

Jun. 2016-Aug. 2016

Administered medications daily, performed first-aid as needed. Tutored and mentored students in Java, Python, and C++.

Technical and Personal Skills

- Technologies: Proficient in: Java/C#, JavaScript, TypeScript, Angular 2/4+, Git, SQL, Relational Databases, Python, Windows 7/10, Linux, LAMP Stack, LaTex, ROS
 - Competent with: ASP.NET, C++, TeamCity, Octopus Deploy, Bamboo, MSBuild, PHP.
- o General Business Skills: Useful presentation skills, performs well in a team, effective communicator.